[Music]
the stoa
is a digital campfire where we cohere in
dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of what's happening now
hey teddy i can hear i can hear you
peter yeah
just okay cool margaret maybe say
something to uh
yeah hi teddy hi hi margaret how's that
coming through
uh faintly but but it's beautiful
all right it's a whole lot better than
nothing okay let's do this okay
um when i want to kick start the intro
so
we can start fresh margaret sure
okay hi everyone thank you for being
patient with our technical difficulties
welcome to the stoa stoa is a place
where we cohere and dialogue about what
matters most at the knife's edge
of this moment and today we have with us
teddy taptic
teddy is the co-founder of the human
methods lab
an organization that's dedicated to
building better ways of working together
he is also a principal researcher at the
between us
project where he focuses on cultivating
human differences
as a generative resource and he is also
the creator
of entangled bodies an unfolding
relational practice which he is here to
tell us about today welcome teddy
thanks margaret i i caught a little bit
of that
and it sounded really flattering
so mission accomplished so um
so you're are you hearing me through
through zoom or through my
phone we are hearing you through zoom
loud and clear crystal
clear that's cool
okay so i just want to uh i want to do
i'm going to put the phone down because
i get an echo so you can hear me now
yes um i'm going to start with a shout
out to the stower i think the idea of
the stower
that invites people to bring
their practices and their different
forms of work
to a gathering is just such an amazing
idea
and such a generous idea and
i really appreciate what peter
and and and you margaret are doing here
um and while i've been preparing for
this meeting i've had a chance to
you know mosey around things on the star
and
the more i see the more i enjoy um
this this particular uh engagement this
conversation
uh starts off with the idea of
narcissism as a kind of siren call in
our society
that we're at a point where there's a
kind of
deep tug towards
the preoccupation with self that has
a whole lot of historical reasons
and and the term preoccupation with self
is itself quite resonant because
preoccupation literally means
filled up beforehand in other words
when we are conscious of ourselves
and our attention and our faculties are
drawn towards
our own performance and how we have to
be
in order to uh deal with the world
then this really dries up our capacity
for paying attention to what's going on
we are pre literally preoccupied
um and so many things and
and the more i think about this i see
how much of our society how many of our
institutions
exaggerate this preoccupation the kind
of
cvisation of the self you know at its
worst
we we think about everything in relation
to how it's going to look
to uh to a kind of
imagined public and
and this is a serious challenge
when we have so many things that we have
to
deal with in the world unless we can
begin to free ourselves with this
preoccupation
we're in deep trouble well as we
evidently are so what i wanted to talk
about
today is some escapes
some ways of escaping from this
narcissistic tug
and and in a way what i want to do is is
um
see my own work as as gathering jigsaw
pieces of
understanding that try to make a pattern
um and that jigsaw and that pattern
isn't complete
um and you know i'm just
one person doing this and we have
examples of
many others for example on the store who
are doing it
i i liked i listened to one star
conversation
uh where ria beck was talking and she
described herself
ria beck would be in in in the maori
world a
kuya that is a uh an elder and a wise
aunt
but she described herself as just a girl
from flanders
and i thought i really liked that
and and so my
my point is i'm just a boy from new
zealand
um trying to figure some stuff out
uh hopefully with the rest of you so
here are some of the
the jigsaw puzzle pieces one comes from
tyson juncker porter who
peter mentioned in the introduction to
this session
and tyson has
quite a lot of wisdom to impart but i
think
for me it it distills down to one big
piece of wisdom
which is that the cycles of
nature that surround us
and um shape our world
are bigger than us much bigger than any
human effort
and so our task is to work
with those cycles um to
to understand them to connect with them
to resonate with them and this is a
a big uh uh this is so different from
the enlightenment
which was an attempt to to find
ways for humans to be masters and
possessors of nature
that's that's not the way and you know
tyson who speaks out of a kind something
between
60 000 and a million years of
um backstory um i think rightly points
out
the opposite and then another jigsaw
puzzle piece comes from my friend
tana mortera in
of rongafakata he's he's a maori
um kind of a young elder
and he like tyson has many kinds of
wisdom to impart but
the one that the jigsaw puzzle piece
that i thought
mentioning here is is his
sense that it's the connection to place
to a particular place to a particular
locality
and the conditions of that locality and
the people of that locality
that gives shape to lives that gives
shape and and a sense of belongingness
to people and with that shape
people learn to grow into their own
purpose
and their own difference so
um on the mirai people discover
their best selves and how to how to how
to work those best selves
and that's a deliberate part of the
the environment and the practice there
so that's
that's a powerful jigsaw puzzle piece
that we could
speak more about and it's especially
important in in our kind of
nomadic existence um we're
we've found ways of avoiding any
attachment to place um
another jigsaw puzzle piece is is about
group rituals this is this is something
that
um that is starting to be
talked about and recognized even though
uh the human experience with group
rituals is
again eons long because group rituals
capture
deep wisdom and experience and and turn
them into
sequences of human activity that
makes sense um bonita roy
in the same podcast that ria beck was
talking about
uh brings tells the story of elk hunting
in canada
where the elders
bake the shoulder i think it is of the
the consumed elk on the fire and the
crack
tells them where to go for the next hunt
and this is a practice of deliberate
randomization
so that so that the animals don't get
hunted out in one place
um the the group the deep wisdom and
experience
in ritual that i have been subject to
most vividly is the work on the maori
mirai
around encounter the practices of
encounter the
uh there's a there are very complex
rituals
that govern how visitors
meet visitors they're called manuhiri
meet the people of the place
the tangata fenua and
these rituals set out and govern steps
in in the practice that means that
people who meet as strangers come
slowly and deliberately into
relationship
and finally into a place where they're
able to make
sense with one another and this sense of
slow and careful and stepwise engagement
really inspires me and i'm
doing my best to uh to see if we can't
find something in our world that would
allow us
to achieve that same level of deep
connection
um uh you know in in
in a practice that slowly orients people
to
the same place um
another jigsaw puzzle piece is that
group
practices these these practices that
groups have learned in order to become
effective together
reveal when we look at them they re
reveal the importance of
physicality and attunement
that is the uh by physicality i mean
all of the capabilities we have as
as human animals and how we can
use those in productive ways and
attunement in the sense that we
use these faculties to pay serious
attention and to focus
our energies in a particular place
and and direction i have i have a kind
of
a sort of parallel to bonita's elk
hunting story from
a tribe in africa that hunt for spiny
anteaters
and spiny anteaters live in
large burrows earth burrows
that that are full of tunnels
and when when the tribe
tracks down a spiny ending to anteater
and
uh in order to hunt it um
they've evolved a practice where one
person who's particularly
physically adroit climbs into the
anteater's nest and works
their way through the tunnel while the
other members of the tribe
listen very carefully at and at each
moment from the outside
they send signals to the person inside
to direct
uh direct them where to go so here we've
got this
really powerful sense of very very
careful listening and attunement that
that embraces a whole group of people in
which they're all
physically and mentally engaged
another great example in our world is
is the rugby field you know the rugby
field is a
i don't know how many of you follow
rugby union it's a national passion here
in new zealand
but at its highest level it involves
people in relationship
to something that's happening at a very
fast pace and is flowing very very
rapidly but each person is
conscious not only of the steps they
need to take
but but the capabilities of each of the
people around them so
they're making physical responses
from moment to moment from second to
second about
which move to make and um
you know as i say in a really highly
skilled team this is
this is an extremely adroit piece of
work
the the one that i suppose
brought the possibilities most vividly
home to me
was spending time at a drama school
here in new zealand where
the teachers had learned to operate
as as a team we we had three or
four teachers and there would be like
students in the room a big studio
and the work of the teachers was
to the teaching practice was to respond
and work
to the needs in the room so the
curriculum
was the folk who were present
and what was going on with them and the
job of the teachers was to
pay attention sufficiently closely
that they could make the moves that were
necessary
to invite the students to
higher levels of capability and
attunement
and but what that meant in practice was
that
they had to divide their efforts so that
you know one person was
making an offer to the class and
their two or three colleagues were busy
reading the room and noticing the
movement
and where the attentiveness needed to go
how was how was the offer landing
and how did that landing need to be
improved
how did it need to be uh made
as as as best as possible
for the work to be done and that for me
was an inspiring model of what i
imagined
we might evolve as group practice the
the idea that we could be um
able to work together to the needs in
the room whatever the needs are
and be sufficiently attuned to each
other
to be constantly kind of passing signals
from one to the other so that the work
proceeds as effectively as possible
and everyone is involved
you know i'd be curious to figure figure
out how to do that
uh here in a medium like zoom but
there's probably
a few too many for me to do by myself
but several of us might might succeed
so this this um recognition of
of rituals and practices
um makes me wonder you know can we
make our own practices and rituals
that capture our own wisdom and
experience one
one ritual that's been happening in
these
um in these worlds of of online
gatherings
is is the check-in
so the check-in is a kind of ritual
for settling people
allowing them to become settled as they
um as they arrive and i
you know i'm curious about whether that
ritual can be
further developed could could it have
more layers
could it have like a developmental layer
as well as
a settling layer could could there be
um could there be a kind of
uh an order of
conversation of of check-ins maybe
the the elders speak first and the
newbies
speak last for example could it include
something like the pharaoh the
challenge that happens on the maori
marae this is an extremely important
step in this process of encounter
that i described at a certain stage
the um the hosts
lay down a challenge to the to the
guests and
when the guests if the guests agree to
accept that challenge
what they're doing is they're agreeing
to follow the
practices and uh and kind of rules of
engagement
of that place so it's more than it's
it's
it's not a trivial um test at all
these kinds of things i i i i
imagine could help our encounters work
better
um so
the aim of the work that i'm involved
with
is is trying to promote readiness to
face the drama of the world
um in in all of its complexity
and uh and and i think the
the state i'm hoping
that we might learn to reach is best
described in the words of my friend john
shotter
as a state of poised resourcefulness
could we learn to be
resourcefully ready to deal with
whatever happens
together um and it might be i i'm kind
of wondering whether that notion of
poised resourcefulness
has an echo in peter's ideas of stoicism
and
and the the virtues of the store
i'm not sure about that yet but i'm i'm
looking for that
i'm looking for that connection
and we've been learning this is another
jigsaw puzzle piece
that the development work the learning
work
happens best in small groups
the the group that my friend rich
bartlett calls a crew
which is around
something between four and six people um
and for me five is kind of a magic
number here
and uh the crew is an arena of
deep curiosity uh
playful experimentation trust
and complete acceptance so
it's it's it's a place where you you
feel
uh able to take risks
to be to try different ways of doing
things to try to be in the world in
different ways
and the the outcome and these are other
kind of jigsaw puzzle pieces i wanted to
lay
in front of you the outcome is something
that
mikhail bakhtin the russian philologist
described
as a unity of unmerged voices
this is what we're trying to achieve is
a unity in which
the identity of each voice remains
present and apparent
um so so that's that's quite different
from
you know uh consensus for example
uh or or the more traditional ways of
of of making decisions that we know
um this is this is the idea that there's
a kind of unity of purpose but it but
each person's
um own uh
uh orientation is not suppressed
but but is still present in in
in the work
and then the the kind of last piece of
jigsaw puzzle
i wanted to talk about was the fact that
this
this work is is kind of learning how to
land
in the midst of others it's it's
learning how to recognize
rather like those teachers i i mentioned
at the drama school
what happens as we gesture as we
offer as we speak to be aware and to
notice
how that's being taken up and then to
if we have the ability to pivot to
a place where that things land better
you know there's a moment um
there's a moment that really sort of
challenged me about less than a year ago
i was in a meeting that i i'd come to a
meeting that i thought was going to be a
really productive
encounter and i discovered something
about myself in that meeting that i
i hadn't realized before i
i'd always thought of myself as a person
operating in a world of other persons
so you know i i i could be like
a blank canvas but what i learned in
this meeting
was that i i was actually
um an old white
male um
and and was being seen very much
in that light that had never occurred to
me i hadn't thought of myself as old
and i suppose i knew i was male and
i suppose i knew it was i was white but
i hadn't
realized that that was a way that i
could be seen and and heard and so
anything i said was going to be filtered
through that
identity um
so so but but that's that's how it is
you know that's uh without recognizing
that i'm not gonna land properly
so that was a real sort of revelation to
me which
has come for me relatively late in life
perhaps for many of you
something like that can happen earlier
but anyway so i i've been
burbling bubbling along in this font
imagining that i'm just you know
another person but actually none of us i
suppose are just
another per person we're always
seen through you know filters and and so
on
um and and with that recognition of
myself
as an old white male
comes a recognition of danger
that you know i could very easily
be seen as just another old white man
with just another scheme for fixing
things
um and and i'm very conscious
of how many you know white males there
are with schemes for fixing
fixing things even in especially in the
networks that we
belong to um and and i'm
i want to resist that very strongly i
don't want to be
an old white man with a scheme for
fixing things
instead i want to try and swim in the
current of
what's happening and you know contribute
where i can
and and and especially that's about
avoiding
intellectualization and
um and the development
and and articulation of ideas my my
friend john shotter who was really my
most
powerful mentor used to tell me that
who used to say you know the last thing
we need in the world
is another idea there's already
lots and lots of ideas um
what we do need is some work that
enables us to develop
to do things together so with that i was
going to propose to do
a piece of listening here now this is
going to be challenging
because you'll be able to listen but i'm
not sure how well i'll be able to hear
your listening
so one way we could do this is i could
um play a short piece of
audio and then maybe
we could use the chat
and does that make sense to you margaret
uh and and what i wanted to do to make
it
a little bit manageable is just
invite a sort of small group of people
to do the responses but then we can talk
about them
as a whole
now um
i was thinking of asking my friend jenny
to be one of those
doing the responses because she's been
doing some of that but
but who else would like to stick their
hand up and and have a listen
so maybe if you'd like to do that can
you
i can't really see everyone can i really
raise your hand or
raise your participant hand a lot of
folk but
um so all we're asking here is
uh for a little bit of listening
and responding on the chat
okay so i'm seeing antonia
full jeff isaias jenny
i i don't feel like picking it
so i just threw out five names oh i'm
also seeing okay and also let's let's
throw theodore into this
right isaias he's put his hand up cool
um kitty can you hear me
there's there's two participants raised
hand yes
probably maximum of five okay
yeah three or four would be probably
ideal i think um
isn't it who else okay
uh theodore fiesta i see raised hands
yeah okay that's the
that's three people it's good just one
more it'd be good
okay so let's do jenny
um isaias there's the little feast i say
yeah
cool dan and antonia
is that too many sorry jeff
okay um okay margaret you're gonna
you're gonna do it too we're good okay
oh full jeff
now you've got the margaret well done
you've got in fact you've got
yeah great now what i have to do is use
my uh i have to play
how do i do this i i play it over zoom
and nigel you helped me to find the way
to do that yeah peter if you
can let teddy share a screen he should
better work for now computer audio is
that going to work
okay so what i'll do
is i'll just play this anyway and you
can tell me whether
you can hear it
coming shortly so it's about a couple of
minutes long
and you're simply going to listen and
then
say what you hear here goes
the result i'm seeking is for them to be
able to pick up that stumbling rock
and play with it and not be afraid of it
and not let it be something that is
going to be
um
a brick turn into a wall in their lives
so whenever they come across
[Music]
a situation that are similar to the ones
that of course that
that are present in the stumbling block
like um it might be that when i was
little
i was never heard
example a kid in high school come along
and
behavioral problems to the max in school
hitting out frustration all of those
things and he would either
freeze or run or hit out
they were his things he would he would
just be so intensely
tied up inside that he was either cast
and didn't want to move he just shut
down
or he would it's a frustration would
build to a point where he needed to do
something about it
um i or he would
it'd be too much for him and he'd just
have to take himself off
but in a way that wasn't positive
i had a very limited amount of time with
this boy because i only just found out
about he was up for suspension and stuff
so i hauled him off and um
just we went for the okay what are you
feeling when that
when it happens when you're feeling like
that
what is it and we got down too he
doesn't have a voice he doesn't know how
to say
what he's feeling and it builds up
builds up builds up until it keeps too
much
and it becomes a wall so it's and
what we identified from really from
there was that
he was way younger than all of his
cousins and all of his brothers and
everybody growing up
and he was always told to go away to
shut up and he was put down
and all that deal to him so he couldn't
ever he never had a voice
he was always ignored he was um and
stuff if they were playing a game
he was the one that was they had all
these things
and all of that frustration that he
contained that he had when he was little
was still what was the stumbling block
now and so when you come into the same
situation
he would use the things that he had back
then which was like if you can imagine
like a four or five year old frustrated
kid that has to just sort of like
head out at somebody because he's
hurting so much inside because
he doesn't know how because no one will
listen
okay so um if
one two three four five six you know
five of you
could simply on the chat
right what came up for you most
strongly in that piece
uh
okay i think that's no not quite
okay there's some
interesting things there
playing with obstacles as a way of
releasing self-expression
and potentially unlocking trauma
um
that's
okay okay
so so just looking looking at what's
come up
isaiah's is has given a really nice
uh sort of summary or description
of of what's going on
theodore i think he's
kind of making a criticism or
or just an observation
i think maybe maybe it's like a
challenge to the
methodology that we we heard
uh full jeff
is
uh that's
is is kind of drawing back from
the details and comment he's kind of
generalizing
as i understand it the the
drawing kind of a general lesson from
from the piece
jenny's talking about the sound really
of what she heard
antonia is concentrating on
on the sort of the feeling of of
what has been heard and dan is
describing it should i be doing talking
on the phone as well no
no the phone's stopped anyway
um
so there's quite a range of
kind kinds of
uh listening but
what we're going to do now um
is play it again and see what you notice
this time
the same people um
and and now you've seen what other
people have said
that might influence what you
notice this time around you're going to
hear exactly the same piece
so i'll play it again starting now the
result i'm seeking is for them to
be able to pick up that stumbling block
and play with it
and not be afraid of it and not let it
be something that
is going to be um
turn into a wall in their lives so
whenever they come across
um a situation
that are similar to the ones that have
caused that that are present in the
stumbling block
like it might be that when i was little
i was never heard
example a kid in high school come along
and
behavioral problems to the max in school
hitting out frustration all of those
things and he would either
freeze run or hit out
they were his things he would he would
just be so intensely
tied up inside that he was either cast
and didn't want to move and just shut
down
or he would that the frustration would
build to a point where he needed to do
something about it
um i or he would
it'd be too much for him and he'd just
have to he'd take himself off
but in a way that wasn't positive
i had a very limited amount of time with
this boy because i only just found out
about he was up for suspension and stuff
so i hauled him off and
just we went for the okay what are you
feeling in there
when it happens when you're feeling like
that
what is it and we got down to he doesn't
have a voice he doesn't know how to say
what he's feeling and it builds up
builds up builds up until it gets too
much
and it becomes a wall so it's and
what we identified from really from
there was that
he was way younger than all of his
cousins and all of his brothers and
everybody growing up and he was always
told to go away to shut up
and he was put down and
all that deal to him so he couldn't ever
he never had a voice he was always
ignored he was
um and stuff if they were playing a game
he was the one that was
they had all these things
and all of that frustration that he
contained that he had when he was little
was still what was his stumbling block
now and so when you come into the same
situation
he would use the things that he had back
then which was like if you can imagine
like a four or five year old frustrated
kid that has to just sort of like
hit out at somebody because he's hurting
so much inside because
he doesn't know how because no one will
listen
okay if if you could
um just and i'm gonna
try and listen hello
yeah so um if you could now
the same group of people could perhaps
uh write down what did you hear that was
different
this time around
so what was the kind of new thing you
noticed
wow
hello
so
there's some quite dramatic shifts here
um
isaias uh
from his kind of description the first
time around
he says honestly i just wanted to hug
this little boy
who was ignored by his family
um now that's a really
interesting shift um
and i'd like to kind of come back to
that
let's just let's just look at some of
the others
fujif
i see
yeah in full jeff's case um
we we we've got another kind of lesson
now jenny
i think jenny is going kind of deeper
into the
feeling of the person that's talking
uh antonia
uh has noticed that it's a kind of
office context yes
professional context that's yep
understanding
dan talks about the urgency and theodore
says um i heard the hopes of the adult
more
than i had the trouble the hopes of the
adult that's
that's really interesting yeah the hopes
of the adult so
um you know one of the things i've
learned is that um
it's possible especially by
repeated listening to hear more
than we normally hear when you know
in ordinary conversation things kind of
fly past us
but but the reality is there's an
enormous amount of richness
in human communication and to
um to to pay attention to it and use it
take some kind of training and learning
and and this this was a very kind of
quick and
simple example of this um
yeah antonio talks about the speaker's
intention
so now what so there's a number of
things going on here so
so people are starting to hear the
aspiration
behind the voice which is more than just
the words the person is using but
kind of what they're reaching for what
they're trying to do
um this is a very kind of bactenian
idea by the way just to mention um
bakhtin again because he
he reckons that if you that every time
we speak we're not we're never just
speaking to
the person in front of us we're speaking
to you know
kind of posterity or to our parents or
to something beyond
and the point the point that he makes
that i agree with is that if you listen
carefully
you can hear that aspiration and the
aspiration is really valuable because
when you
when you tune in not just to what a
person is saying but what they're
reaching for what they're trying to say
you can connect it with your own
aspiration
it's a great way of building connection
and relationship
because you know it turns out that we
don't
always say everything that we are
thinking
but nonetheless there's there's often a
kind of presence in our voice
and if we listen closely we can hear it
um the the the kind of
we're coming up to the end of the r so
we can't go too much further with this
but
i i what i want to draw out is one
crucial dimension of the practice of
attunement and and this was
best described to me by again my friend
john shotter who passed away
about four years ago but he talked about
the difference between
aboutness and withness speaking
about in aboutner speaking um
the thing that we are discussing is kind
of
over there it's we're talking about it
we are describing it as something that
is
quite separate and distinct from
ourselves that's one way of talking
this is the conventional view of science
for example
but a lot of a lot of uh
ordinary talk is is very much about this
talk as well
and there's a spectrum that goes from
aboutness
and at the other end of the spectrum is
something that john called
withness and in witness speaking
we are deeply engaged with whatever it
is
what whatever the phenomenon that we are
discussing
is and i played you this piece
because i think we can hear
how engaged this speaker is with
the thing he's talking about we can hear
as
some of you have seen his is noticing
uh sorry his aspiration but
he he's he's tending
much more towards witness speaking in
the sense that he
inhabits the situation of the child he's
discussing
he doesn't waste time on judging the
person
um but but but instead
just tries to to
to get inside the experience of the
child to feel it
and then figure out what to do as a
result
and that that was what led him to this
understanding that the child didn't have
a voice
and the end of the he's a social worker
as it happens and
the end of the story was that he helped
the child find the voice
uh the child was able to speak and and
the
behavioral problems um
went away in the family so anyway
that's that that's kind of the end of
that story but
the purpose of playing it to you is is
twofold firstly to
illustrate this idea of a spectrum of
ways of speaking that reaches from
something that's quite detached to
something that's quite engaged
about nurse to witness and secondly
to demonstrate that the practice of
listening itself as we've done
can reveal details and
and and understandings and meanings
that otherwise bypass it bypass us
in this kind of practice i've discovered
that i mean we can listen to the same
thing
even three or four times
and and each time we can hear something
new
and recognizing that something new
is the beginning of a practice of
tuning ourselves in a way that we can
recognize how our own
words and gestures land with others
and i'm not saying this is easy work and
i'm certainly not suggesting that
i know all about how to do it because i
i screw up all the time um
but uh but but there's this tantalizing
state out of reach this this notion of
poised resourcefulness that i think is
is potentially obtainable by a group of
people
who take one another seriously enough to
engage at a level of detail in their
speaking and gesturing and then become
much more powerful
in the way they deal with other with
with others
and you know i've seen serious practical
examples of this happening
and i think it could be enormously
helpful as a force in the world for good
if we can figure out how to develop it
ourselves that's kind of the end of
my my old white man uh
speech gene i'm pleased to see you're
laughing
at that idea
hello okay
right okay thank you teddy for sharing
and making the best of a less than ideal
tech situation there was still a lot of
richness and at least for me personally
that came out of
listening to you share about your jigsaw
pieces and the inspirations and
hopes that have cultivated developing
this practice
i feel hopeful that people here will
have another opportunity to experience
it in its full glory
as i know when
peter and i participated in um a round
of it with you it was really
uh the richness was unexpected of just
how
deep the rabbit hole goes of the
possibilities
and self-learning and skills that
can be developed through this so thank
you very much for
taking the time to share with us um
i have to say it was a pretty weird
experience
not being able to hear you all but i
hope maybe we could do something where
that's possible i
i thank you all for coming um
there was one question in the chat
around how
can people follow up with this practice
yeah well this is uh absolutely this is
a big
a big experiment that we're developing
we have a website called um
between hyphen us.net
where we set out the bones of the
experiment
um and we're really inviting people to
join in
we're looking to conduct workshops with
people still
on a kind of voluntary basis because
we're still building the practice
peter was peter and margaret were kind
enough to join
a four session workshop that we just
concluded and i think
we learned we did some good stuff but we
learned there's more to do yeah and you
know next time around it's going to be
better
yeah well we you know we'd love to have
you back and there's always
an opportunity to test things out here
at the store i know there's lots of
interested people who would be willing
guinea pigs in the experimentation
yeah yeah deep martial arts practice
that's
absolutely right yeah that's a beautiful
simile
thank you for that now
yeah okay
okay i feel like it was
it's so strange not being able to hear
you but it's lovely to see your faces
just the same so
thank you all for joining and we'll do
it better next time
yes thank you teddy thank you very much
and thank you all for attending uh
hope to see you again at the stoa
and um perhaps
experience entangled bodies in a
different manner next time